the diamond way
course uh we took the best of all the
diamond way
books there are
990 teachings from Lord Buddha that
still
exist we finished inputting them about
15 years
ago so we saved uh all of the teachings
in the world that Lord Buddha gave we
finished them 15 years
ago they are online and they are
free but they're in
tibetan
uh so out of 990 guess how many of those
books are diamond
with about
500 okay it's almost exactly
how our Diamond
way and
uh that course that seven-year course in
Diamond
way
30,000
pages I think it's the best Diamond R
course in
history those books were because it was
secret uh different parts of Asia have
different parts of the diamond wave but
nobody has all of
it
and it took it took like 35 years of
work and I think it's the best diamond
way course in
history so it's crazy if you don't do
it and uh I think the gule heart
teachers are are some of the best
teachers if you want to learn diamond
ring uh I had a meeting with them
yesterday they have worked harder than
any other country to learn it that way
I'd like to thank
[Applause]
[Music]
them
why am I talking about
that well try to study with them
okay and they're doing a good job on
it uh but here we have a t
offering and uh TMA means um it's like a
special
cake and it has special ingredients in
inside and like if your family is having
some kind of
problem like if you don't have Harmony
in the
family or one of your family members got
cancer something like
that it's a
tradition to make this cake it looks
like this shape right oh there's a
picture I think I have a
picture
yeah there's a
t uh we teach you how to make
them and when you're having a serious
problem you make one and you put it
outside your front
door and it helps to protect the
family now let's read lojo
[Music]
for for Lo
person if they get
sick they should thank the
spirits because
we were supposed to do
Tong we are supposed to take other
people's
problems if you get some kind of
illness you should think I did
it I took the other people's bad
seeds and I got
sick
so you should be
happy
then you should make a
t and go put it outside your
house you can thank them but you can
also say I hope new spirits will come to
make me more
sick so normal
people when they get a family problem
they make a
t and they put it outside their
door loj
people when they get a
problem they make a
t they put it outside their
door and they say this is an invitation
to more sickness demons please come this
is the place you want to come
to
and I will take it from other
people if someone has to suffer it
should be
me okay and it's very funny because the
TOA meaning outside the house is like
when we do the tto when we do
the diamond way Retreat and we put the
Mantra on the
door
it's supposed to protect the
house I did a retreat in the forest
North in North
Arizona I put the mantras on the four
walls and I did a one month
Retreat and there was a forest fire
and I saw it coming uh it was jumping
from the top of the tree to the top of
the tree it didn't touch the
J and it was coming down at my cabin you
know and the fire the firefighters
came five of them
died they they have to hide under the
special
blanket when the fire goes over
them and between me and the fire Five
Guys
died so I did Mo we call Mo means
prediction with the
di should I run or
not then they said no you don't have to
run
you have those mantras on the wall you
don't have to worry you
know then I'm like I don't know I think
I'll
[Laughter]
run and I pack a bag and I ran you
know there was a
highway I ran to the highway and I hitch
hike and I I went to town and I stayed
in a hotel you
know
then uh I realized I forgot my address
book and next day I I went back to see
if it survived the
fire and I went to the all the forest is
burnt you
know and I walked through the
forest then I came to my cabin
it's fine it's no
problem the Fire split and go around the
cabin and
continue then the guy I rented the cabin
from he's standing in front door and he
says I love you
guys those Buddhist mantras they're so
cool
and he saved like $50,000 house you
know but this one is
different and if you're L
person you put the Mantra on the house
to attract the
fire if someone loses their house it
should be
me it's advanced
[Music]
Buddhism all right if someone's gonna
lose their
house it should be
me this Mantra is not to stop the fire
this Mantra is to invite the
fire it takes a lot of
Courage but that's
Lo in English we say are you man enough
to do Lo are you woman woman enough to
[Music]
do are you strong enough to invite
problems and eat the other people's
problems okay that's
loo and it takes a lot of
Courage but the more you eat other
people's
problems the more good seeds you plant
there was a a llama he was
dying he's a very famous
llama very peaceful
llama and he was on his
death and he's going no no
no no then his students are like what
happened what's
happening no no no you know no he said
what's wrong he said I'm Lo
person I was praying to go to the hell
after I die so I can help
[Music]
people and the angels are trying to take
me to
Heaven he's very
upset no I'm supposed to go to the
hell they are said no you have to go to
he's like
no okay that's a real
lojo by the way he ended up in the
heaven I'm
sorry okay he failed to go to the
hell because he wanted to go to the
hell to help other
people so we are not like that we are
not so
strong take little problems from other
people they say start
with they say start with giving away
vegetables and then you can give away
later you can give away your
life for me giving away vegetables is
very
easy give away churo is a
problem all right
M okay
uh if you're gonna give if you're gonna
make
Tas you should offer the TOA to the bad
spirits and say thank you for hurting
me you are the instrument of me using up
my BCA
anytime someone gives you
trouble I don't get much trouble from
people except when I
drive I don't know in Arizona special
drivers there always in always in a big
truck you
know they always follow me like this you
know
then I give a special
sign you know I have to do secretly
because my wife doesn't like
it she's like everything okay honey
I but uh if you're
lo you have to thank those
guys thank you for thank you for
following me too
close you are using up my bed
seat in fact inside the Dharma
organization be careful when someone
thanks
you maybe it means you're a really
problem
person thank you I love
you why why you love
me because since I know you I use up so
many bad
seeds Okay that's real
[Music]
person this is a very important uh ver
you guys got that par
it starts
with it starts
[Music]
with yeah the green one the green
one this one is very very important
okay it's good that we reach it
today uh let's say that you walk into
your
kitchen and there's water on the
floor okay probably it happened to
you and
then you have two
choices you can get some towel and you
can clean the
floor and you feel you feel okay you
feel
happy you know I clean I clean the the
floor the water's
gone but in
Buddhism if you don't look under the
sink you're a stupid
person find where the water came
from okay don't just clean up the
Mist maybe you have a water leak in your
house then I I know I feel usually I
feel lazy you know Daniel
knows sometimes I get a link under the
sink in my
kitchen and I will clean up the floor
and I will call
[Music]
Daniel hey can you figure out where the
water coming
from
I I'll tell you a
secret if you want to find out what kind
of underwear the plumber is
wearing tell them there's a link under
the
sink then they you can see the big but
and sometimes I'm watching
Daniel but
uh I will
send you go check the water
and I feel lazy I don't I don't want to
crawl under there
you it's dirty and it's
hard and I feel I just feel really lazy
to to clean
it and but if you're
Buddhist our job is to find the source
of the
leak first teaching of Lord Buddha
pain and the source of pain that you
have to find the source of
pain don't be
lazy crawl under the S make sure your
underwear is clean and then crawl under
the
thing and try to find where where's the
real name
okay
when you have a
problem find the real
source and don't be
lazy because if you're
lazy you will have to clean up the water
again and again and
again and uh I'm I'm a lazy
person I will clean the kitchen floor 10
times instead of crawling under the sink
you
know but Lo
person you have to not be
lazy if a person's giving you
trouble you're doing
something that you can keep uh fighting
with
them you can keep talking to
them but it's like cleaning up the
kitchen floor it's it's going over and
over
[Music]
again crawl under the sink find the real
cause and that's
you all all problems all problem people
are coming from
you so you have a choice you can you can
fight with them for many
years
or you can crawl under the S and find
the real
problem and the real problem is
me okay all people who give me problems
are coming from
me Gila should drive
[Music]
home go in the
bathroom close the door look in the
[Music]
mirror
okay right okay that's the real
person if you're going to make the
special welcome
sign you should do it in the
mirror that's the real source of the
problem and that's good because then you
don't get more fights with other people
uh if you want to do a
confession this is a an interesting
suggestion for advanced
confession like you did something very
bad like when I was in college I had an
abortion and I I my teachers taught me
it wasn't a
problem my
colle then later my llama said big
mistake you
[Music]
know and uh I want to clean the
karma you know so then you should you
could make a TOA for
example and uh you could offer it as a
as a
purification and but he says
here uh if you really want to do a
purification offer a trauma and ask for
more
problems do a prayer for more
problems and dedicate it to your
mistake so I made a mistake when I was
18 or
19 and I'm offering
TOA I'm not offering it to the
Buddhist I'm offering it to the negative
Spirits please come to my
house give me as much trouble as you
can and I'm going to use it to clean my
b
okay it's a takes a lot of
Courage by the way then when you meet
irritating people you can
celebrate oh my T offering was
success uh this is a famous
quotation tell say
K every single thing that happens to you
during the
day use it for your
meditation okay
everything okay especially your
problems so if you're a low Jone
person and you're driving to the airport
and you have to get there on time
and there's a bad traffic
[Music]
jam people ask me G did you go to Mexico
it means did you go to Mexico
City the people from New York they say I
live in the
city and you're like look there's other
cities
also
then the people from Mexico say I live
in
Mexico you look like there's other
Mexico besides Mexico
City anyway my memory of Mexico City is
five hours sitting in a traffic time
without
moving and uh when something like that
happens to
you in
Lo you have to use it for your
meditation okay
here means any problem comes to
you take it as a meditation
object so you don't have to you know go
to a temple to find a meditation
object just go to the highway in
downtown
Mexico and you get an automatic
meditation on to
it okay so if you're real loj
person everything that happens all day
long you can use
it don't tell me don't come to Gesa and
say I need meditation object for the
next six
weeks I need a meditation object for the
next six weeks
okay I have a
suggestion use your
life that's the idea everything that
happens to you can be a
meditation here it
says person who's studying
Lo they can use everything in their
meditation
immediately okay uh we reached the
fourth of the Seven
Points since we don't have the young man
to ask what is number
four I'm sure he took his mom to a nice
lunch in
guara with the money
uh we reached point for is a summary of
the whole lifetime
practice and we're gonna I'm going to
start it but also the guar
teachers they're going to teach it to
you the last two
days there are 18
sections actually 22
total they're very
sexy and uh we're going to do it the
last two
days so I'm going to start uh like an
introduction to
that okay
she the essence of a lifetime
practice is
called and it means the five
powers
uh and they are called
the carpos it means the power of the
white
SE number two
is by the way I'm not going to pay $100
for
this you could just skip
it to means get used to
it P is number three
uh make a resolution or motivation for
the
future
number uh destruction
Power number
five
prayer okay what does it
mean uh the first one is called I like
to call it do you have a next item you
guys
yeah uh I like to call it toothbrush
toothbrush
meditation and uh I found out recently
that Steve Jobs used to do
it so he dropped out of
college he built the first Mac
computer
his mother uh yelled at him because he
didn't finish his
degree and he used to go back to college
and sneak in the classes to make his
mother
happy and one day he he snuck into a
class about
Buddhism and they taught the teacher was
teaching impermanence
meditation
and he never finished the
course but he learned uh impermanence
meditation and he did it every morning
for the rest of his
life uh when he's brushing his
[Music]
teeth and uh he say to
himself if I die
today if I have to die
tonight how should I spend this
day and so for the his whole
life he did this uh death
meditation when he's brushing his
teeth okay and and
then he gave a beautiful um talk at
Stanford
University he got uh pancreatic
cancer it's a very quick cancer and
there's no
cure and uh they asked him please give a
talk to the graduating
class and it's a a beautiful talk it's
on YouTube you should see
it he's one of the most creative people
in modern world in the Modern
Life
and he talks about death
meditation uh he talks about uh every
morning when he brushes teeth he he will
think this is my last
day and it comes here in the
Lo and by the way it's not uh depressing
or
sad it's
true if you brush your teeth
and you say today I will
die one day it will be true
okay that's not
stupid it's
true and then you it's a it's a strange
thing when you face your
death every
morning and you say I will die before
tonight you feel much more relaxed
okay the whole
world is trying to
pretend I cannot die
today but it's a
lie so there's a conflict in your
heart on on one side you know very well
you can die today and you will die today
someday
and in the other side of your own heart
you're thinking no no I will live
forever somebody has to be the first
person to live
forever there's a famous movie song is
called it's
me maybe I'll be the first person who
doesn't
[Music]
die just in case maybe you should do the
meditation maybe I will die
tonight and it it's not a
sad and it's not
depressing what's depressing is to lie
to yourself day after day after
day
that creates conflict in human
mind your parents your school your
community everyone's training you to
pretend you're not going to
die then if you when if you can do the
toothbrush
meditation look in the mirror and say
honestly yeah maybe today
it's so
relaxing to to admit the
truth and you're much more
functional then you can really have a
good
day okay and it's not
sad what's sad is to pretend you're not
going to
die that's like you have a big dead and
you pretend you you have
money it doesn't feel
happy just admit what's going
on then you can
relax okay so here's the loong death
meditation as soon as you wake up in the
morning
I Will Not Waste this year I'm sorry I
Will Not Waste this
life I Will Not Waste this
year and in particular I Will Not Waste
this
day and I will do something
useful
what's the most useful
thing I will fight the greatest enemy in
my
life who's the greatest enemy in your
life for
$1,000
but listen the there's a contract
here
$1,000
okay he said today I will fight the
greatest enemy in my
life every day when you wake
up today I will fight the greatest enemy
in my
life I will take three guesses and no
more I will offer
$1,000 but the answer answer has to be
exact and I'm not paying $1 for half
answer that's like half butt or
something you know okay so I want both
I now it's not me it's
Rob he's GNA have so many friends by the
time we
finish I'm just predict your next few
days God you look so good this
morning don't believe
it I hope we have enough there we have
enough okay all right okay it's up to
Rob by the way I want an exact answer
and I'm not going to be afraid to say no
if you
don't I'll repeat the
question when you wake up look in the
mirror and say today I will fight my
biggest
enemy and for a Lo person what is
that it has to be exact or I'm not
paying and there's only three
chances okay ra make yourself
unpopular wait wait wait
microphone Jo
h
no the suspense is killing
me I think if it takes more than one
minute let's cancel
[Music]
it
I am my worst enemy that's not exact
I'll give you one more
chance it has to be more
ins same person more
exact I don't care if you ask for help
that's very
loal
think about
myself selfishness think about myself I
want one more
[Applause]
[Music]
word
taking your husband to dinner I
[Music]
hope by your desert for yourself
okay all right yeah uh today I will
fight my biggest
enemy every time I want to take care of
myself first I will fight
him every time I want to take the first
one
myself I will fight
it you know as soon as they bring in the
Turles I'm waiting
do you know how embarrassing it's going
to
be if I go back to
Sedona and my wife says how is the Cho
this
time and I say Veronica honey they
didn't give me any
chur I mean she'll say why you go to
[Music]
guara there's hinting and there's direct
statement I'm direct I tried the hinting
it didn't work
exist yeah
but I will try to share before I
eat okay I I I won't take the first
one definitely I'll take the second
one but uh I will fight my enemy
okay all right I you want to hear a
funny
story I went to teach in Mexico
City and uh it was a big crowd it was a
thousand
[Music]
people and uh my friend I forget who was
it my friend came uh uh just before the
program
I forget who it was but they said gesla
my mother made Turtles for
you because you always talk about
chur and then uh I said okay cool you
know and but we were supposed to play
some
music and I asked Nick I think Nick Nick
I'm not saying his name I
[Music]
mean I told Nick uh please hold these
churos and
uhur for me and we're going to sing a
song and
then we sing who was the girl singer I
forgot AA the microphone didn't work for
10 minutes and we we did a
song and we finished the
song then I went backstage to get my
chur and Nick is like
this I'm like hey Nick where's those
churos he's like
Nick you know I said I can't believe you
guys
they yeah I was going to use the churro
in the
top and I look behind the curtain I'm
like Nick bring me a
churo he's like
[Laughter]
Nick when you say when you say Nick next
time
say okay anyway uh so when you wake
up look in the
mirror today I I will fight my greatest
enemy my Habit to take care of myself
first like Nick
did I mean I'm just giving
example actually he's a very very kind
he's one of the kindest people I
know
[Music]
uh
P he
says uh
don't don't cook lunch without thinking
about the promise he made in the morning
that's
all then he says uh people like you and
me don't forget he's talking to like
5,000
monks
when we get up we put on our ropes and
we tie the
belt there's a special knot that you use
in the monks the Monk's belt is just a
rope you
know and it's a lot of fun with the new
monks because they don't know how to tie
it and it's always falling
down so G lar taught me how to tie my
knot you
know he says the moment we tie the knot
in the morning the moment you tie your
belt
right you should make a plan for the
day okay I don't know button when you
button your
shirt you know have the button should be
connected to a plan for the day
you know when you close the first
button you should already have a plan
for to
do how to fight your
selfishness and what He suggests is
connected to part of your
clothing maybe when you button your
pants when you button your
shirt uh use that time
to make a plan for fighting your
selfishness
today and it's very
powerful okay if you make it a
habit it's very very
powerful okay so connect it to part of
your
clothes when I button my shirt in the
morning I will try to make advanced
attack plan on myself
okay that's called into that it's called
Pon
P make an advanced
plan next
picture actually I have a
suggestion
uh let's can we do some question and
answer uh we have 20
minutes I feel like we over we ate too
many Dhat
Turtles I think we need to relax a
little
bit don't forget the thing about your
shirt and let's just do questions for 20
minutes relax have something to
Dr you have to tell Veronica I drank the
green
she says we have churos for
today in English we say I believe it
when I see
it any question any by the way any
subject I don't
care
thank you for
the thank you for the beautiful teaching
[Music]
Michael M my question is for beginners
in this
audience and they're learning the Lo way
and they're supposed to take on all
these
problems they don't have the capacity
yet so what should they do what should I
do as a beginner to take on more
problems for
myself
actually I think the best thing is
emptiness
meditation so I have a limit of a number
of how many problems I can
take
um so in my heart I have an idea how
much I can I can do I have a limit in my
heart
and like we brought
the we had the idea to bring the
ukrainians
refugees and uh I talked to John and
Connie I put pressure on
them I said me and Veronica will pay for
two and you pay for
two they're like Okay
g and then uh like a few days
later I thought this is going to be hard
to pay for for five four or five
people their rent is 2300 a
month you know I I start to doubt
whether I can do
it and then I said yeah I can it's
empty the apartment rent number is
empty it's a everything is
empty okay what does it
mean a problem is not difficult from its
own side
[Music]
it's
empty empty means a problem can be a
good
thing a problem is not a bad thing from
its own side and a problem is not a good
thing from its own
side that's the emptiness of
problems so by the way emptiness doesn't
mean you go a stare at the wall and
close your eyes or something you
know that has nothing to do with
emptiness emptiness
means you can see everything two
opposite
ways problems can be
opportunities success can be a
problem okay so everything's
empty so when I had this Ukrainian rent
doubt I I I agreed to pay well we agreed
to pay their expenses for two
years then I got nervous I start to add
up that's that's the rent is 25,000 a
year
you
then I thought uh how many people came
to
Japan for Grandpa's Abo's birthday
party we had some good music from
Cuba and uh so
I we were teaching a teaching
there King
sh
he gave exactly 50% of his body
away he gave somebody his
legs and uh it's mentioned in the L but
they don't tell you the
story so uh I found the story because of
John Brady's
datab and then we translated it and we
made a book and we gave it away for free
you can get it online by the way for
free Diamond Cutter
press.com they are also giving away
ebooks of all the ACI courses I mean
they one by
one
and I think they just finished one in
Spanish uh I'll let you know
tomorrow I think it's I think they're
giving it away I'm not
sure and it took the whole week in Japan
to teach that
story but there's two
stories understand okay I didn't teach
the Second
[Music]
Story you want to hear the Second
[Applause]
Story by the way it answers your
question okay so here's the story I did
not tell in
Koto and it's the answer to your
question and it's my own answer to my
own question about how am I going to pay
the
rent
and uh they are
available first two ACI courses and we
should thank the Spanish translation
team especially the director Rosa van
grien so
uh are you used to go around the world
and buy
gemstones what is that one the light of
oh yeah that's a new
book I used to go around the world
buying gem
Stu Sri Lanka has a lot of gem
Stu because of the geology I don't
know in ancient times it was called
ratna
rat ratna means Jewel like three
jewels means
Island and Sri Lanka is the island of
jewels I had a direct experience of
that went to colbo which is the
[Music]
capital to buy
gemstones and we also used to cut there
we used to cut a lot of
stones and my friends asked me you want
to go to Candy do you want candy I said
yeah I'm happy to have
candy my friend his name is uh Mr G
ratna he said uh no no I'm not talking
giving you candy I'm taking you to
Candy there's a famous temple called
candy in the middle of Sri Lanka on the
mountain then we drove there it was a
long
drive and the road was a little bit
rough
[Music]
and uh I said I have to pee
pee and so he pulled over just on the
side of the
road he said go behind that tree be
careful you don't meet an
alligator and I went behind the tree and
I pee pee and I looked
down and there's like rubies and
Sapphire then I'm like
wow I took a whole pocket for home you
know it's really the island of
jewels you just go to PE and you get a
bunch of emeralds you
know so in the old
days people used to take a ship from
India to Sri
Lanka
and there's many stories of the ship
breaking there was a famous story which
I will not tell you
today about a boy who didn't drown his
name
was
MRI and uh s translated that book and he
named his son
Mel
so anyway there was another uh ship that
broke and there was uh so all the guys
fell in the water between Sri Lanka and
India and in that lifetime Lord Buddha
was a sea turtle a big
turtle and
one by one he he go to the Sailor and he
say he he point to his back and they
hold his back and he takes them to the
land to save
them and but when he comes close to the
beach there's a special fish called
pirana you know
piran
they like
turtles so he's like hm uh if I go close
to the
beach this piranha they they bite you
and they
suck but if I don't go close to the
beach the guy will drown those those
humans will
drown so he decided he will swim into
the beach you
know and one by one the Piranhas
are they catch him and they start to
suck his
blood that's the story I didn't tell in
Koto why am I mentioning
that one more piranha is not such a big
deal I can do the Ukrainian
rent already I'm you know the money is
going here here here here
here it's just one
more and and you can see the emptiness
on
it you already every day you're already
solving many problems for yourself and
your
family so just just add one more doesn't
matter my life is already
hard I already have to pay a lot of
things every
day so what the hell I add one
more and that's the emptiness of the
problem so uh I personally don't accept
that you have a limit I don't accept the
idea that you have a
[Music]
limit you can always do
more and
uh and I I I understand that my teacher
told me well sometimes you have to
rest and I believe
that but I say Your Capacity is about a
100 times more than you
think like when there's a war or
something suddenly you see people who
who become Heroes
right they like already tired and they
pick up five people and carry them to
the to the fighting you
know I think you have more power than
you believe than you
know it's just
uh what do you call it um
determination if you if you decide to do
it you can do
it and and then it becomes the new
normal to have more
bills that's okay you know so my my
personal
opinionin person people told me Gua your
health is not so good you you shouldn't
start three new projects this week you
know
and I'm like what the hell you know just
do it you know
so I I think you can you can always do
more if you want to you have to work on
the on the courage it's not a physical
problem it's a courage
problem you can do much more than you
think
that's my my opin that's my
experience okay one more
[Music]
question you
like who's
choosing is a question from online
participants online thank you Michael
for teaching us
today um this is a question from
[Music]
Nancy she's from what's that old town
outside of Montreal outside of yeah
gu when you ask her what's the name of
your
town and when she
sneezes uh that's actually the name of
her
Tong Okay Go Okay uh she's asking I work
with small children and in our school we
are seeing a drastic increase of autism
with young childrens what seeds do I
need to work to clean this
up
[Music]
uh so I have a nice
answer my whole life I didn't have a
television and I didn't watch television
for I don't know 60 years or
something then during Co I got a bad
habit
it's called
Netflix and uh to be honest I start to
watch it
sometimes and uh then when you start to
enter the Netflix
culture Netflix when you meet your
friends you're like what did you see
anything good on Netflix got any suggest
I ask Ellie you got any suggestions for
me yes and somebody said uh
try uh the extraordinary attorney woo W
it's a it's a Korean uh soap
[Music]
oper and um it's about a young woman
from
Korea and she has
autism and it's a 16
[Music]
episodes uh about one to one and a half
hours and it's extremely beautiful
Dharma
teaching I really encourage you to see
it and it's talking all about the
difficulty of autistic
people
and I had a um so I went to California
one
time and uh this woman asked me to come
to her
house and she introduced me to her son
he was about five years
old and he has
autism and she asked me is there
anything we can do to help
him
he can't use the seed system because he
can't understand
it so we made a cool
plan we will buy gifts children's
gifts and we will take him she will take
him to the children's
hospital and they will sit next to the
children and like cancer children or
something and then she puts the toy in
his
hands and then she takes his hands and
she moves it over here and she lets it
Go and and he he lets the toy into the
other kid you
see 9 % of an action is
intention but 10% is the actual
action so he doesn't get the 90 but he
gets the
10 and she went over and over to the
hospital with him and he and he got his
10% which is called uh completion Karma
he he didn't get the intention Karma
which is 90% but he got the 10% doing
it two years later I was back in Califor
near San
Jose and she said come to the
house
so I was uh she said sit
down and she called the
boy and he came in
and she said play play play Uncle
Micah's
song and he sat down at the
piano and he's
like and he played like a whole
classical song
memory and now he's a
musician you know something happened in
his
brain from the seats
okay so I think we can help uh autistic
kids to do the
10% and that will start to change their
karma
and actually autistic kids uh their
problem is that their attention is too
good their attention span is too
strong so there's things you can help
them with and I think you can help them
to plant
seeds because intention is is 90% but
10% is is what we call
completion and for me that's a useful
trick I think it will even work in
growth the name of her town
is you want to hear a nice
story
uh she's the the sister of Jerome and
Angelo
giov and their mother came to Diamond
Mountain she she was about 85 at the
time and uh she came for a whole Retreat
to D
mountain and uh she did she did The
Retreat and then uh she went home to go
[Music]
out and next week uh they called
me and they sent me a photograph and she
has a she's standing with a beautiful
rosary and I said what's the
photograph and uh she came from Sicily
Italy like uh when she was 5 years old
or
something or something like that a te
teenager and she had a
rosary that her mom gave
her and she lost it 70 years
ago and she prayed about it at
d
when she came home to
go she open the drawer and it's right
there so that's a nice
story okay uh see you guys
tomorrow and thank you for translation
from
[Applause]
[Music]
Flavia oh